brother.com 2018-04-16

# Brother International - Privacy Statement

**Privacy Policy**

**(Last Updated: January 25, 2018)**

Brother International Corporation, and its subsidiaries ("Company," "Brother", "we," or "us"), are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. We know that the privacy of personal information is an important concern to our customers. 

This policy covers information that is collected through Brother websites, including [www.brother-usa.com](http://www.brother-usa.com/), [www.brothermall.com](http://www.brothermall.com/), [www.brothercloud.com](http://www.brothercloud.com/), [https://v7.omnijoin.com](http://v7.omnijoin.com/), [www.brothermobilesolutions.com](http://www.brothermobilesolutions.com/), [www.brotherthinkoptimize.com](http://www.brotherthinkoptimize.com/), and [www.ibroidery.com](http://www.ibroidery.com/), to which it is linked ("Site") and to the use of our products and/or services ("Services"). This Privacy Policy is a part of, and is incorporated into, any Terms of Service between you and Company which are applicable to our products and/or services. This Privacy Policy and such applicable Terms of Service (together, the "Agreement") comprise the entire agreement and understanding between you and Company with respect to your access to and use of the Site and Services. 

Brother International Corporation (and its subsidiary companies Brother Industries (U.S.A.), Inc. and Brother Mobile Solutions, Inc.) participate in and have certified their compliance with the EU-U.S. and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework. Brother International Corporation is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>. 

Brother International Corporation is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequent transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Brother International Corporation complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Brother International Corporation is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Brother International Corporation may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

This statement describes (i) the types of personal information we collect, (ii) how we use and protect the information, and (iii) to whom we disclose information. 

PLEASE REVIEW THIS PRIVACY POLICY REGULARLY. By using the Site and the Services, or providing your Personal Information (as defined below) to Company, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Site, the Services, or provide your Personal Information to Company. To the extent that any terms or conditions of this Privacy Policy conflict with the applicable Terms of Service, then the Terms of Service shall govern, except as to the extent (if any) otherwise expressly set forth in either this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service. 

The Site and the Services are generally intended for adult audiences. Company does not knowingly collect, disclose or use any Personal Information of individuals under 13 years of age for marketing, solicitation or any other purposes, other than for lawful purposes related to the operation and maintenance of the Site and the Services. 

**Collection of Personal Information**  
**Personal Information is any data that can be used to identify an individual.**

The Personal Information that you may be asked to provide when creating an account or registering for our services may include your first and last name, mailing address (including ZIP code), e-mail address, password, billing contact information, telephone and, if applicable, your employer's name and address. 

When purchasing the Services or products online, you will also be asked to provide a credit card number. The credit card details that you provide when purchasing products or the Services constitute Personal Information that is covered by this Privacy Policy. 

We may also collect certain information about your access to and use of the Site and the Services, such as the name of the Internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the Internet, the dates and times that you access the Site, and the Services, the pages that you view while at the Site, and the Internet address of the website from which you linked to the Site. Information regarding your computer system configuration and operating system is also gathered. This information is used by us to help analyze trends and to improve and administer the Services. 

We also display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@brother.com](mailto:privacy@brother.com). 

If you receive newsletters or promotional e-mails from us, we may collect additional information about you through the use of customized links or similar technologies to determine whether the e-mail was opened and which links were utilized by you in order to provide you more focused e-mail communications or other information. 

We collect your location-based information for the purpose of providing you with information (such as job postings) specific to your location. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service. 

You may opt-out of location based services at any time by editing the setting at the device level or by emailing us at [privacy@brother.com](mailto:privacy@brother.com). 

For OmniJoin Users: 

When you invite attendee(s) to use our Service, we will collect information from them such as their name and email address. We will automatically send your attendee(s) a one-time email inviting them to your event. Company stores this information for the purpose of sending this one-time email and providing the service to your attendees. If you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [omnijoinsupport@brother.com](mailto:omnijoinsupport@brother.com). 

Your online transaction with Company will be conducted through a secured transport utilizing HTTPS and SSL encryption, with secure certificate services provided by a major third party security certificate provider such as VeriSign. As part of some of the Services, we (i) will process personal facial images and sound data, (ii) collect and log information generated from the computers of participants, including without limitation information regarding which participants viewed presentations, engaged in an exchange of information contributed to written materials, shared applications, posts, or printed or downloaded presentations, and (iii) collect detailed polling results identified at the user level, including without limitation how each individual user voted. This information is shared with a subscriber hosting a conference. 

The Services incorporate Error Logging and Reporting ("ELR") that captures error report data and, at your option and only with your consent, sends this data to Company via the Internet. Error report data is used to assess and correct errors or problems that may occur during use of the Site and the Services. ELR error reporting is automatically triggered when the Service detects a software error. ELR error reports collect information about what was occurring with the Services when you experienced the problem and about your computer's configuration. It is possible that ELR error reporting may collect Personal Information, business information or other information as part of the error report. For example, a snapshot of memory may include your name, portions of documents that you were viewing or sharing during the conference in which the error occurred, portions of any presentation that you were viewing or sharing during such conference, or application or desktop data that you were viewing or sharing during such conference. 

If you are concerned that the ELR error report may contain Personal Information or other information that you do not want to disclose, please do not send us the ELR error. 

**Use of Personal Information**

Company may use your Personal Information to provide you with more effective customer service, to improve the Site, and the Services, and to make the Site easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the Site to your particular preference or interests, among other uses. 

Registration information collected is used by Company to validate users, manage subscriptions, recall user settings (address book etc.) deliver Services, support and improve the Services evaluation process. You may abandon registration at any time before completing the registration process. With regard to Personal Information that is collected during the registration process from our users, we present the option not to receive communications from Company regarding the Services and other product information. If you do not wish to receive such communications, you may opt-out or unsubscribe. We present the OPT-OUT option to all users, except with respect to system or service notifications. Each communication that you receive from Company will provide you with a method of opting out or unsubscribing. 

We may also use Personal Information to determine your eligibility for our free trial offers. Your email address may be used to send you periodic product offers and usage tips. You can opt-out of promotional emails at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions in the communications you receive, but will still receive communications such as receipts, confirmation emails and customer service updates that are considered necessary to provide the Services to you. We use the Personal Information collected to deliver Services, process payments, update our records, communicate with you about products and services and generally maintain your accounts with us. 

If you indicate an interest in receiving e-mail communication, we may periodically send you information about other Brother products and services that Brother feels may be of interest to you. Established users will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals and/or newsletters. Occasionally we may invite you to participate in surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose personal information. The requested personal information usually included contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code), but the specific personal information collected in any survey may vary. Personal information will be used by the contest or survey sponsors to notify the winners and award prizes and as otherwise provided in the applicable contest rules. You should carefully review the rules of each survey or contest in which you participate, as they may contain additional important information about Brother's or a sponsor's use of your personal information. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of your personal information conflict with this privacy policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall control. We will not share the personal information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice. 

Company may disclose Personal Information if we determine that disclosure is required by law, other legal process or is requested by a public or governmental authority: 

  1. to comply with any law, regulation, or litigation; or 
  2. to protect and defend the property rights of Company and its Affiliates; or 
  3. to act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of any officer, director, employee, consultant, agent or representative of Company, any user of Company products or services including without limitation the Site and the Services, or any member of the public; or
  4. for reasons of national security, law enforcement or other issues of public importance.
  5. In the event Company goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.
  6. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

**Sharing of Your Personal Information**

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, Personal Information that you provide to Company will not be shared outside of Company and its Affiliates including companies established in the U.S. and Japan. Neither Company nor its Affiliates will sell your Personal Information or otherwise make it available to third parties, except as permitted by you through an opt-in permission request or as otherwise outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

In providing the Services to users, Company is required to provide some of your information to third parties in order to perform activities associated with the Services. Examples of these activities include billing processing, live chat software to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order, and fulfillment and sending e-mails on our behalf. When you sign up for our Services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that Service and only to the third parties who we believe provide appropriate data security protection. 

Brother shares aggregated demographic information with its business associates and advertisers. For example, Brother may, on a periodic basis, present information such as the number of users, areas of interest, relationship to Brother, etc. This is not linked to any personal information. 

**Updating Your Personal Information**

Upon request Company will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your Personal Information changes, it is your responsibility and obligation to update it. If you wish to change, review, delete or update your Personal Information, you can do so by logging onto your "My Account" page. You can access or update your Personal Information and communication preferences we have on file. If you require assistance in updating or accessing your Personal Information, ask to have it removed from a public forum or if you would like to request that your account be marked as inactive, please contact us at [privacy@brother.com](mailto:privacy@brother.com). We will respond to your request within 30 days. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Security of Your Personal Information**

We are committed to protecting the security of your Personal Information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the Personal Information you provide to us on computer servers with limited access. When we transmit sensitive Personal Information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we transmit it through the use of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption or other technologies. 

The Personal Information that you provide to Company in connection with registering as a user of the Site or the Services (such as your name and e-mail address) is protected in several ways. For example, your access to your registration information is available through a password and a unique customer ID which is a valid e-mail address provided by you. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. In addition, your registration information resides on secure servers accessible to only selected Company personnel. Company encrypts your Personal Information and strives to prevent unauthorized parties from viewing such information when it is transmitted to Company. We utilize security data security methods appropriate to the risks presented. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us [privacy@brother.com](mailto:privacy@brother.com). 

For OmniJoin Users: 

Any information (including without limitation Personal Information) that you submit during your use of the Services is available to all persons participating in a conference. The information you share during a conference (including without limitation Personal Information) may be read, collected or used by others for any purpose, including sending you unsolicited messages. Company is not responsible for any information that you elect to submit while using the Services or for any use of such information by any party. 

We do not disclose your private, online communications ("Content") with Company to any third parties other than as outlined in this Privacy Policy. However, your Content is available to those whom you authorize to see your Content as well as all other parties with whom your Content may be shared, including any other participant in your conference. Additionally, any participant in a conference may record and retransmit your Content. In the event that you elect not to use any of the Service's security access controls, the Content that you share in conjunction with your access to or use of the Site and the Services is available to those in the general public who are aware of the URL address for your conference. Such Content may include, without limitation, data, packets, information, communication or other material that is transmitted, copied, uploaded or otherwise made available through the Services using your log-in ID and password. 

**Tracking Technologies**

We and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, scripts, or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to help the website recall your specific information to deliver relevant content and eases website navigation, when you return to the website. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited. 

In addition to cookies, the Site gathers information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP/Internet address of your computer, your browser version, referring URLs and general web visitor information used by our web traffic reporting tools. This information may be linked to your registration information, and your navigation around the Site may be tracked. We use this information to understand how the Site is being used so that we can improve the Site and offer appropriate products and services to our customers. 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails in order to count traffic or determine readership statistics. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. 

We also use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 and Flash to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here: [**http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118** ](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118)

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Site may include Social Media Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These Widgets may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Widget to function properly. Social Media Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Widgets are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Links to Other Web Sites**

The Site may contain links to third party websites. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the Site, the Services, and to the Personal Information collected. You acknowledge and agree that Company is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third party websites, for your use of any third party websites, or for any intended or unintended consequences of such use. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit. 

Please understand that some sites provide geographic choices when you enter the Site. Upon selecting a geographic area, however, you may be redirected to a different site, with a different privacy policy. 

**Assignment**

We reserve the right to transfer any and all information that we collect from users to a third party in the event of any merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of Brother's assets or stock (including without limitation in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings. 

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will revise the "Last Updated" date at the top of the Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about our policies and procedures concerning privacy, including how we are helping to protect the Personal Information we collect. 

Your continued use of the Site and Services constitutes your agreement to and acceptance of this Privacy Policy and any updates. You will be deemed to have been made aware of, and will be subject to, any changes to the Privacy Policy immediately upon the posting of notice of such changes on the Site. 

**Company Contact Information**

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, or if you believe this Privacy Policy has not been complied with, please contact Company by e-mail at [privacy@brother.com](mailto:privacy@brother.com). Please include the word "privacy" in the subject. You may also contact us at Brother International Corporation, 200 Crossing Blvd, Bridgewater, NJ 08807. 

In your correspondence (whether sent by e-mail or postal mail), please ask your question in detail or describe in detail the ways in which you believe that the Privacy Policy has not been complied with. We will investigate your question or concern and will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly provide an answer or otherwise to determine and remedy the problem. We will reply to you by the same method (either e-mail or postal mail) by which you contacted us.
